salary.com 2012-06-08

# Privacy Policy

**_Privacy Policy_** ** __******

The following statement describes the privacy practices for Salary.com, a division of Kenexa Compensation, Inc. (including its divisions and wholly-owned subsidiaries) ("Salary.com"). Following this introduction, this statement is divided as follows:  (A.) Salary.com's Online Privacy Policy, which addresses the privacy practices applicable to usage of the Salary.com® website, (B.) Salary.com's SaaS Privacy Policy, which addresses the privacy practices applicable to information processed by Salary.com in its role as a Software as a Service ("SaaS") provider and (C.) Salary.com's General Privacy Provisions, which apply to both the Salary.com website and Salary.com's role as a SaaS provider. 

Salary.com respects individual privacy and strives to collect and use personal information in a manner consistent with the laws of the countries in which it does business. Salary.com abides by the Safe Harbor Principles developed by the U.S. Department of Commerce and the European Commission. More information about the U.S. Department of Commerce's Safe Harbor program can be found at [http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/](http://www.export.gov/safeharbor). Salary.com also abides by the principles established in Canada's Personal Information Protection and Electronic Documents Act ("PIPEDA"). 

**A.   Salary.com, Inc. Online Privacy Policy** ****  
This Online Privacy Policy covers use of the site www.salary.com. All information disclosed by visitors is subject to this Privacy Policy. With respect to data received through its websites, Salary.com will comply with the following:

**1.          Types and Uses of Information** ****  
Salary.com gathers personal information from site visitors from time to time in order to enhance existing offerings or provide additional services. The company gathers only the information essential for understanding visitors in such a way as to provide better compensation and talent management products and services. This may include contact information such as name, email address, telephone number, and company name, and perhaps other data. 

Salary.com also may monitor customer traffic patterns and site usage to help refine and improve the design and layout of the website as well as the user experience. As a result, Salary.com automatically tracks certain information about site visitors. This information includes the users' browser type, most recent URL and the next URL that the user visits, regardless of whether these URLs are on the Salary.com website or not. Salary.com also will track visitors' IP addresses. Salary.com uses this information to, among other things, identify broad demographic trends that may be used to provide information tailored to users' interests. 

Visitors may choose to purchase detailed personal salary reports and other compensation offerings. In order to do so, visitors must disclose detailed personal information including demographical, compensation, work experience and salary related data. In addition, visitors are required to register and receive a logon name in order to be able to access and use certain features of the Salary.com website.   
Any personal information given to us through our website is used exclusively by Salary.com unless otherwise noted on the site. Salary.com does not make this information available to third parties who trade or rent information for direct marketing purposes. 

Salary.com does not collect e-mail addresses without the site visitor voluntarily providing us with this information (typically via our online information or demo request form, whitepaper request form, and other website forms and surveys). Salary.com will periodically use that contact information to send visitors e-mail or other communications for sales, service, support and marketing purposes. Visitors who do not wish to receive marketing e-mail from Salary.com in the future may opt out of receiving these communications by following the instructions included in each communication. 

**2.          Third-Party Ad Servers** **and alternative Third Parties**  
Salary.com may use third-party ad server companies to serve or present the ads that appear on the Salary.com destination website. These companies may use information about you and your visits to the Salary.com and other websites in order to provide advertisements on the Salary.com destination website and other sites about goods and services that may be of interest to you. We may partner with advertising networks to help present advertisements on our sites, including online behavioral advertising.  These advertising networks use cookies to help present, better target, and measure the effectiveness of their advertisements, using data gathered over time and across their networks to determine the characteristics and preferences of their audience. Salary.com may also set cookies on your computer during your visit to our website on behalf of third parties other than third party ad server companies or third party network advertising providers. These alternative third parties collect non-personally-identifiable data and information regarding your internet use and the sites you visit. They may use this data or information to: (i) provide data or information products and services to Salary.com which may be used internally or, Salary.com may sell or distribute such data or information to third parties; (ii) provide data and information products and services direct to third party customers of the data collector. Salary.com does not authorize these third parties to store personally identifiable information about you in their cookies; nor for their own internal analytics. 

If you would like more information about this practice or to opt out of having this information used by companies that are part of the Network Advertising Initiative to provide targeted ads, please visit <http://www.networkadvertising.org/optout_nonppii.asp>. 

**3.          Credit card information** ****  
When a customer places an order online with Salary.com, their credit card information is protected through the use of encryption such as the Secure Socket Layer ("SSL") protocol. SSL makes it difficult for credit card information to be intercepted or stolen while being transmitted.

**4.          Cookies** ****  
Salary.com and its advertising partners may use both per-session and persistent cookies to enhance the user experience while visiting the Salary.com website. Cookies are small bits of data stored locally by a browser that saves information and helps the hosting website identify the user upon subsequent visits. Cookies are uniquely assigned to the users' computer and may only be read by a web server located within the domain that originally issued the cookie. Cookies generally assist users by performing certain functions such as saving passwords and personal preferences regarding the sites. Salary.com also uses a third party targeting cookie provided by its authorized third party partner’s tag. This cookie is used to record a user’s site behavior. It is a persistent cookie. 

Persistent cookies are stored for a set length of time determined by the web server when it passes the cookie on to the browser. Persistent cookies are used to store information between visits to a site.

Per-session cookies are used to store information only within a session. These cookies are cached only while a user is visiting the web server that issues the per-session cookie. Per-session cookies are deleted from the cache when the user closes the session. Users may have the ability to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but users can typically modify browser settings to decline all cookies. Alternatively, users may modify browser settings to provide notification each time a cookie is tendered, permitting the user to accept or decline cookies on an individual basis. If a user chooses to decline cookies, however, it may hinder performance and negatively impact the user experience on Salary.com's website, and ultimately, the use of any hosted compensation and talent management software. 

**5.          Disclosure to Salary.com partners** ****  
Salary.com does not provide detailed information about individual site visits, nor the information users provide, to outside companies without users' permission. Salary.com may share aggregated information about the use of this site to companies with which Salary.com has business relationships. This usage information, such as numbers and frequency of visits, is used to attract appropriate advertisers to various areas of the site. Salary.com provides this data so that advertisers and other businesses can better understand how people use partners' content and the Salary.com site, with the goal of providing the best possible web experience.

**B.   Salary.com, Inc. SaaS Privacy Policy** ****

**1.          General** ****  
Salary.com is a provider of Software as a Service ("SaaS"). As a SaaS provider, Salary.com provides its customers with a suite of compensation and talent management solutions that provide organizations with more efficient and effective means to compensate and reward their employees. 

Salary.com serves as a data processor for the clients who use Salary.com's products. Customers of Salary.com's hosted talent management, payroll or compensation solutions fill the role of data controller. Salary.com maintains only that information which its customers have asked it to process and processes it only upon, and in accordance with, the customer's direction and instructions. This SaaS Privacy Policy does not reflect the privacy practices of Salary.com's customers, and Salary.com is not responsible for its customers' privacy policies or practices. Salary.com does not review, comment upon or monitor its customers' compliance with their respective privacy policies, nor does Salary.com review its customer instructions to determine whether they are in compliance with or conflict with the terms of a customer's published privacy policy.

This SaaS Privacy Policy applies only to the transfer of personally identifiable information ("Personal Information") received by Salary.com in any format through its hosted solutions, whether supplied directly by Salary.com customers or by employees or users of the hosted solutions anywhere in the world, including transfers from the European Union and Canada to the United States. With respect to data received through its hosted solutions, Salary.com will comply with the following: 

**2.          Notice/Use of Personal Information** ****  
Salary.com supports a hosted system, where it collects Personal Information including but not limited to customers' organizational data (salary and compensation figures and structures, job descriptions, job codes, reporting relationships), employee data (specific identifying information such as name, email/physical address, current/previous base salary, performance ratings, skills, skill gaps, qualifications, certifications, gender, ethnicity, language, picture, resume and other demographical information), market data (salary surveys that clients have purchased) and other data required to provide payroll and HR services for customers and their employees. Salary.com operates as a data processor for its customers. Salary.com maintains only the Personal Information which its customers have asked Salary.com to process and processes it only upon, and in accordance with, the customer's direction and instructions. It is the responsibility of the customer to ensure that the data the customer collects and later gives to Salary.com can be legally collected and disclosed in the country of origin. The Salary.com customer is responsible for giving its employees and users the appropriate level of notification that Personal Information is being collected and maintained. The Salary.com customer also is responsible for ensuring the security of any method used by the customer to provide Personal Information to Salary.com if through means other than the hosted solution.

**3.          Onward Transfer** ****  
Salary.com is a global corporation with operations in several countries. Salary.com has developed global data practices designed to ensure that Personal Information is appropriately protected. While Salary.com's primary data centers are in the United States, Personal Information may be transferred to our offices in other countries. Salary.com also may contract with third-party providers to perform certain functions on our behalf or to enhance our existing product and service offerings. Examples include providing financial transaction, product and service support. If Salary.com discloses Personal Information to a third party or to our employees outside of the United States, Salary.com will ensure adequate protection of such Personal Information. Third parties will have access to your Personal Information only to the extent necessary to permit them to do their jobs; however, they are bound by confidentiality agreements before any information is provided to them and are restricted from using the information for other purposes.

**C.   Salary.com General Privacy Provisions** ****  
These General Privacy Provisions apply to both Salary.com's website and its hosted solutions applications. All information disclosed by site visitors, customers and other individuals or organizations is subject to these provisions. With respect to data received through Salary.com's website and its hosted solutions, Salary.com will comply with the following: 

**1.          Data Integrity and Access to Data** ****  
Salary.com will take reasonable steps to ensure that Personal Information is accurate, complete and current to its intended use. Salary.com will only use Personal Information in ways that are compatible for the purposes for which it was collected or subsequently authorized by the user. 

Salary.com provides users with reasonable access to Personal Information that they provide to us as well as the ability to review and correct such information. In addition, to protect users' privacy and security, Salary.com takes reasonable steps to verify user identity before granting access to Personal Information. Salary.com may limit or deny access to Personal Information where providing such access would be unreasonably burdensome or expensive in the circumstances. 

**2.          Security** ****  
To prevent unauthorized access or disclosure, to maintain data accuracy, to allow only the appropriate exercise of users' Personal Information while also protecting the confidentiality, integrity and availability of users' Personal Information, Salary.com employs a variety of industry standard security technologies. Security is provided on the data, application and hosting level. The security infrastructure includes a physically secure data center, proven firewall protection, intrusion prevention measures, SSL encryption of all data in transit, role based authorization and additional proprietary security measures. Communication to Salary.com servers from a client computer is achieved through an SSL connection. This ensures data, including Personal Information, is encrypted when transferred over the Internet. Salary.com provides further user-based security configured specifically for the individual client's needs. For example, as a TalentManager® subscriber, the client will be able to specify levels of user security, including: domain-limited access (access only from the client's proxy server), password configuration (length, letters, numbers, etc.) and automatic password expiration.

Salary.com limits access to users' Personal Information and data to those persons who have a specific business purpose for maintaining and processing such information. Salary.com's employees who have access to users' Personal Information will be made aware of their responsibilities to protect the confidentiality, integrity and availability of that information and have been provided training and instruction on how to do so.

**3.          Enforcement** ****  
Salary.com has a Privacy Officer who is responsible for Salary.com's compliance with and enforcement of this Policy. Salary.com's Privacy Officer is available to any of its employees, customers, vendors, business partners or others who may have questions concerning this Policy or data security policies. Salary.com's Privacy Officer may be contacted by email at [privacy@salary.com](mailto:privacy@salary.com) or by mail at Salary.com, 343 Winter Street Waltham, MA 02454. If users have questions or concerns regarding this policy, they should contact Salary.com's Privacy Officer before filing any formal complaints with the Better Business Bureau or any other applicable organizations.

**4.          Safe Harbor** ****  
Salary.com adheres to the Safe Harbor privacy framework developed by the U.S. Department of Commerce in consultation with the European Commission's Directive on Data Protection on the transfer of Personal Information from European Union member countries to the United States. The Safe Harbor privacy principles are notice, choice, onward transfer, access, security, data integrity and enforcement. More information about the U.S. Department of Commerce's Safe Harbor program can be found at <http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/>.

**5.          Canada Privacy Principles** ****  
Salary.com abides by the principles established in Canada's Personal Information Protection and Electronic Documents Act ("PIPEDA"). The PIPEDA principles are:

  * accountability/compliance with the principles 
  * identification of the purposes/reasons for collecting the personal information 
  * consent to the collection of the personal information 
  * limiting the collection to only what is necessary in order to achieve the desired tasks 
  * limiting the use, disclosure and retention of the personal information 
  * maintaining accurate data 
  * safeguarding data with appropriate security policies 
  * making policies easily available to employees and customers 

**6.          Notification of Privacy Policy Changes/Choice** ****  
Salary.com reserves the right to change, modify, add, or remove portions of this Policy at any time. All changes will be posted on this page to inform our users what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we may disclose it. We may e-mail periodic reminders of our notices and conditions, unless you have instructed us not to, but you should check www.salary.com frequently to see recent changes. Unless stated otherwise, our current privacy notice applies to all information that we have about you and your account. We will not materially change our policies and practices to make them less protective of personal information collected in the past without the consent of affected users.

**7.          Legal Disclaimer** ****  
Salary.com may disclose Personal Information when required by law or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary in order to conform to the edicts of the law, comply with legal mandates, enforce the terms of use of Salary.com's website, enforce agreement between Salary.com and its customers or to protect the rights, property, or personal safety of Salary.com, its users and the public. 

**8.          Contacting Salary.com** ****  
If you have any questions about this privacy policy, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this site, please send correspondence to the following address.

Web Policy  
Salary.com  
343 Winter Street  
Waltham, MA 02454  

Update effective April 25, 2012
